

João Francisco has been a software developer for over 9 years, holding a bachelor's degree in Computer Science, has been proficiently working remotely from Brazil since 2020. Fond of technology and its ability to simplify lives, prioritizes humanized communication and empathy. Available to work with front-end and back-end. You can contact him at joaofrancisco.dev@outlook.com

### Skills

- TypeScript | HTML5 | CSS3 | React | Sass | Angular
- Node.js | SQL | T-SQL | Highjump / Körber One | Figma
- Brazilian Portuguese | English Professional proficiency

## **Education**

• Bachelor of Computer Science - Univali Itajaí, Brazil 03/2017 – 12/2021

## Experience

**Software Developer** → Körber Supply Chain LATAM Remotely, Brazil | 06/2022 - Current

- Engineered and maintained WMS utilizing **T-SQL**, **Körber One**, **Architect**, **WebWise Page Editor**, **Azure DevOps**, **Jira and Scrum**, prioritizing elevating code quality and achieving a 40% growth rate.
- Formulated and executed WMS project definitions to optimize development methodology, enforcing rigorous code conventions, and enhancing team collaboration.
- Directed sporadic trips to client warehouses to oversee WMS software approval, implementation, and testing; provided leadership to support team on various visits, enhancing operational efficiency and client relationship management, leading to a 15% decrease in software bugs.

#### **Junior Programmer** → <u>Univali</u>

Itajaí, Brazil & Remotely | 05/2017 – 06/2022

- Developed and defined projects including CI/CD, utilizing the following technologies: Angular, TypeScript, CSS3, HTML5, Genexus, Node.js, Oracle, Sass, GitLab, Microsoft Sharepoint and SQL.
- Collaborated on activities with Scrum, keeping sprints every 2 weeks for more than 5 core projects.
- Managed and sustained front-end code using **Angular**, and back-end code employing **Genexus** across three projects such as student enrollment and entry point management for the college.
- Conceived and executed the college's new degree system using **Genexus**, completely digital with **XML**, integrating online with government **APIs** and conducting **XSD** validations.

#### Frontend Web Developer → Univali

- Worked with the development, definition and changes of software, with the technologies: HTML,
  CSS, Figma, JavaScript, Sharepoint (ASP.NET, C#), Photoshop in over ten projects.
- Achieved an 80% improvement in the page loading time on the main college website: Portal Univali.

# Personal Projects

- **Personal Finance Web System:** System for organizing personal finances using **React, Vercel, TypeScript, HTML, CSS** and loading data from **Google Drive Sheets** as a database.
- **Stocks Report Downloader:** Web Scraper to download data from B3 and export it into a csv, xlsx and pdf by loading from an xlsx list of search terms, with **Node.js** and **TypeScript.**
- **PDF Word Search Engine:** project programmed with **Node.js** and **TypeScript** to find words inside 20GB PDFs and 800k search words based on a xlsx list and save on a new xlsx file with the desired information.





